Welcome, everybody, to our lecture 14 of 6 .006. This is our last lecture on graph
algorithms. In particular, the last lecture we'll have on weighted shortest paths.
But we're going to talk about a
slightly different problem today,
different than single -source shortest paths.
We're going to be talking about all -pair shortest
paths. But first, let's review our single -source
shortest paths algorithms. We had BFS, DAG
relaxation. Dijkstra, which we saw last
time, which gets pretty close to linear.
V log V
plus E is pretty close to linear. It's much closer
to linear than the general algorithm we have for
solving single -source shortest paths, namely
Bellman -Ford, which is a little bit more like
quadratic. This is like the difference between,
for sparse graphs, this is like the difference
between sorting using insertion sort in n squared
and merge sort in n log n, for example. We're
going to get actually quite a big bonus. For
large input sizes by using Dijkstra when we can.
Today, we're going to be focusing on this new
problem called all -pair shortest paths. It's not
really complicated. Instead of having a single source,
we are essentially wanting to give in an input.
This is our weighted graph,
where we've got a graph VE,
and we've got a weight function
from the edges to the integers.
This is our general weighted graph.
We want our output to be something like
the shortest path
distance from u to v
for every
u and v
in our vertex set.
That's what we
want to return. Now,
there's one caveat here that
if there's a negative weight cycle in our graph,
in other words, if any of these delta uv's
is minus infinity, there's a
negative weight cycle in our graph.
Or BORT
if g contains
a negative weight cycle.
So we're not actually going to worry about
negative weight cycles in today's class.
If we have a graph, it could have negative weights. These
are any integers. It could include negative weight edges.
But as long as all of our path
distances are bounded from below, none
of them are negative infinity, we don't have any
negative weight cycles, then I want you to output
all of these shortest path distances.
Now, in particular, this output could,
any of these outputs
needs to have size theta.
A v squared.
Because for every pair of vertices, I need to
return to you a number or infinity or minus infinity
or something like that. But we are not dealing with the
case with minus infinity. The output could have size.
This is a theta here. It
does have size v squared.
But in particular,
it's at least v squared.
Because I need to give
a number for each pair of vertices.
And so we couldn't hope for linear time
in the size of this
graph for this problem.
Single source shortest paths for certain versions
of the problem, we need to read the graph. And so
we need to use linear time. But in this problem, our output has quadratic
size in the number of vertices. So in a sense, we can't do better than this.
It's quadratic.
And actually,
what's one way we could solve all pairs shortest
paths by using stuff we've already done in this class?
That's why I put this slide up here. Yeah, we
could just solve a single source shortest paths
algorithm from every vertex in my graph. That
seems like a stupid thing to do. It's almost brute
force on the vertices. But it's certainly a way
we could solve this problem in polynomial time.
And we could
definitely solve it in
order
v squared e time
using Bellman -Ford. We just
take v steps of Bellman -Ford
and deal with
a graph on any set of vertices.
We can do better than this.
We can do better
than this for graphs
that are special in some way. We can do v times
v plus e, v times linear. If our weights are
positive and bounded, we can use BFS v times. Or
if our graph doesn't have cycles, we could use dag
relaxation v times. Or if our graph had non -negative edge
weights, we could get basically v squared log v plus v times e.
And that's actually not
bad. In sparse graphs,
this is what Bellman
-Ford would give us.
But if we had Dijkstra's, for example, if we had all positive edge
weights, non -negative, sorry, we could get v squared log v plus v,
v e time.
This
is v times Dijkstra.
OK. So how do these running times compare? This is
v times Bellman -Ford. This is v times Dijkstra.
Let's just get a feel for this separation here. If we had a sparse graph where v
is upper bounded by the number of vertices, this one looks like v squared log v.
This one looks like v cubed.
And we need to spend
at least v squared time.
Right? So actually, this is really close to linear in the size of the graph.
So we can get this off by a log factor, just like sorting would entail.
And this one
would have a linear factor. Right? In the sparse
graph, this would be a linear factor worse than
this instead of a logarithmic factor. Again, this linear to log separation.
We don't want to have to do this running time if we don't have to.
Right?
That's the name of the game.
All we're going to
do in this lecture
is try to solve how we can
make this running time faster
by doing something a little bit more intelligent than running
a single source shortest path algorithm from every vertex.
OK?
How
are we going to do that? Well,
we could
do this by doing something called the
sparse graph. Let's see. What are we doing?
Right. The idea here is if we had a graph,
should my graph be directed or undirected?
I'm not sure. Let's see if we can make a
directed graph. OK. So here's a directed graph.
Why do I not care about undirected
graphs? Can anyone tell me?
Yeah. It's because
I don't care about undirected graphs.
Because if I had an undirected graph,
I could detect whether it
had negative weight cycles
in
constant time. Sorry, in linear time. I could just
check each edge, see if it has negative weight.
Because a negative weight edge, undirected edge, is a cycle of negative weight. So
I could just, if it has any negative edge weights, I could return in linear time
that it does, and I can abort.
Or it has only positive weights, and I can still
use Dijkstra. So that's all good. So we're only
concerned about needing to run Bellman -Ford on directed graphs
that potentially have negative edge weight. OK. So here's a graph.
Let's see. Is this
a graph that I want?
Sure.
Let's say we've got
that direction and this direction. OK. Say we have a directed
graph like this. And let's say this is s. This is our source.
OK. And we have weights being 2.
Sorry, weights being 4. 1, 1, 2, 2, 2, 2. OK. So
this is an example of a graph we might want to run
all -pairs shortest paths on. Maybe we
also have negative weights in this graph.
OK.
In particular, this has a negative weight cycle. I don't
want negative weight cycles, so I'm going to make this 0.
OK. So this graph doesn't have
negative weight cycles. Great.
That's true. Great.
All right. So here's an example that we might
want to compute shortest paths on. There's no s in
all -pairs shortest paths. But I'm going to be talking about a couple of shortest
paths from s. In my next argument. So I'm just labeling that vertex as s.
OK. The approach we're going to do, we're going to
try to take a graph that has negative edge weights,
directed graph.
We don't know if it has negative cycles or not yet. But we want to compute
all -pairs shortest paths, not in this running time, but in this running time.
How could we do that? Well, maybe it's possible
that we can change the weight of every edge
so that they're all positive, but shortest paths are preserved. So basically,
if a particular path like, OK, the shortest path from s to t here is 1, 2, 3,
right? I could change
edge weights in this graph.
Say, for example, if
I changed 1 to 0 here.
That would still make this a shortest path, right? I haven't done it. I've
reweighted the graph. Shortest paths have to be the same in this graph. But now,
sorry. Yeah.
This is not a shortest path.
OK. I'll make that in minus 2.
And then these both 2. And I think in this 4. Man,
I really should have done my example beforehand.
OK. So this still doesn't have negative weight
cycles. It has a negative weight edge. But this path
is longer than this path. So when this was 1, this
had length of 3, which was shorter than this path
that is length 4.
OK. Cool. So this is the
shortest path from s to t.
I could change weights in this graph. For example, changing 2 to 3 and 1
to 0. That changed weights in my graph. But shortest paths remain the same.
So maybe there's a way I could reweight my edges so that
shortest paths stay the same. Shortest paths are preserved. OK.
So I'm going to put
this back to where it was.
All right. So idea.
Make
edge
weights
non -negative
while preserving
shortest paths.
OK.
In other words, just reweight the edges
here so that shortest paths in g, this is g,
after we reweight, we'll go to some graph g
prime with the same combinatorial structure, just
different edge weights. And we want shortest paths.
We want these weights to all be non -negative.
And we want shortest paths. If there's a shortest path in g, it continues
to be a shortest path in the reweighted graph. That's the goal for today.
If we can do that transformation and this is non -negative,
then we're done. Right? We're done because we can just run
Dijkstra v times
on that new graph,
get the shortest path distances,
construct a shortest path tree from those distances,
and then traverse that tree in the original graph.
And compute shortest paths
along that tree. So that's a claim.
Claim.
We can compute
distances in g.
So we're going to restrict
g prime to have with
non -negative edge weights.
If we have such a g prime with non -negative edge
weights, we can compute distances in g from distances in
g prime in
v times
v plus e,
which is smaller than our Dijkstra running
time. This is our Dijkstra running time.
And this is smaller
than that. So
that would be
fine. What do we do?
We have our new graph g prime. It has all positive
edge weights. We run all pair shortest paths in
here by just running Dijkstra v times. And then for each vertex s, we
have some shortest path tree to all the things that it's connected to.
We can look at that path
in g. This is the same common trial graph, just with different edge weights. We can
look at that same tree. I'm not going to be able to draw the exact same tree here.
But what I can do is I can
just BFS or DFS along this tree.
And every time I have an edge, because each one of these is the shortest
path in this tree, I can just compute every time I traverse an edge
what its shortest path distance is in g in linear time for
that vertex, for that particular s. I do that over all s's.
And I get this running time.
So we first wanted to find,
we were wanting to make edge weights non -negative
while preserving shortest paths. Because if we
could do that, we could solve our
original all pair shortest paths problem.
So this is the proof sketch.
But how can we do this? But how?
It doesn't even seem like this
could be possible generally.
How can I just re -weight the edges and maintain that the shortest
path trees are the same? That seems hard to do. And in particular,
if there's a negative weight cycle
in this graph, it's impossible to do.
So claim, not possible
if g contains
a negative weight cycle.
The exclamation point
is just my comment here.
So if g contains a negative
weight cycle, then in particular,
the shortest path
distance or a shortest path
in g, if this is g, say we have a negative
weight cycle directed cycle c here.
In particular, the shortest path from this
vertex on the cycle to this vertex on the cycle
what is its shortest path? It's infinite. A shortest
path is infinite around this cycle. You just
keep going around the cycle over and over and
over again because it has negative weight.
Weight of c is less than 0, strictly. That's what
a negative weight cycle is. So the shortest path,
a shortest path from s to t has infinite
length. And in particular, is non -simple.
So shortest path from s to t is
non -simple.
But as we proved in the
last lecture, shortest paths
in a graph
with
non -negative weights
are what? Are simple, right? Because
there exists shortest path trees.
So that's a contradiction.
So this is not possible.
So given a graph with negative weights but no negative cycle, it's
still not clear how we could find such a reweighting of the graph.
Can we do this?
Well, we're going to
exploit a little idea here.
How can we transform the
weights of a path? Well,
what's a silly idea? I have this silly idea. If
I don't want negative edge weights in this graph,
this is messy in the back. We've got
edge weights 1, minus 2, 0, 1, 4, 5, and 1.
There's only one
negative edge weight here.
What if I just added a large
number, or in particular,
the negative of the smallest edge in my graph to every edge in my
graph? Then I'll have a graph with non -negative weights. Fantastic.
Why is that not a good idea?
Well, in particular, if I did that to
this graph, if I added 2 to every edge,
the weight of this path,
which was the shortest path,
changed from weight 3
to weight 9, because I
added 2 for every edge.
But this path, which wasn't the shortest
path in the original graph, it had weight 4,
increased only by 2. Now that is the shortest path. Or it's a
shorter path than this one, so this one can't be a shortest path.
So that transformation, sure, would make all the edge weights
non -negative, but would not preserve shortest paths. Right?
In particular, if I added the same edge weight to every edge, I will
bias toward taking paths that have fewer edges, not just smaller weight.
So that first idea
doesn't work. Right?
Idea, add
large
number to each edge.
This is bad.
Makes
weights
non -negative,
but does
not
preserve
shortest paths.
So this is not a
good idea, bad idea.
Is there any way you can think of to modify the edge weights
in a graph in any way that will preserve shortest paths?
So here is an
idea for you,
which is kind of this critical step in Johnson's
and a lot of graph transformation algorithms.
If I have a vertex,
say this middle guy,
say v,
every path
from v goes through
an outgoing edge of v.
And every path going into v
goes through an
edge going into v.
I haven't said anything, I've said very stupid
things. But that observation is critical here. If I
add a number, or let me see if I got this
right in terms of adding and subtracting.
If I add a number to all
outgoing edges from a vertex,
and I subtract that same number
from the weights of all of the
incoming edges to that vertex,
then every path from v is changed by the same
amount, because every path from v goes through one of
those outgoing edges. And any path going into v has also changed by the same amount.
In particular, it's changed by a negative, whatever we added to the outgoing edge.
So such a transformation,
adding a number from all the outgoing edges from a vertex and subtracting that same
number from all the incoming edges, preserves shortest paths. That's a claim. Idea.
This is a better idea.
And subtract
weight to all incoming edges.
So that's the idea.
And the claim is
this transformation,
shortest paths
are preserved
under this transformation.
And why is that?
Exact same argument
that I had over there.
Proof.
Consider any path in my graph.
If the path could go through v many times, or it could go through
v not at all, if my path, if I have a path in my original graph, g,
then with path weight
w of pi, this is my path,
it goes
through v some number of times.
So I'm going to say
this is going from s to t.
If it never crosses v, if it never
touches v, the vertex that I transformed,
then I argue that the path weight is the same, because
I didn't do anything to edges that are in this path.
Alternatively, this thing goes through v
sometimes. If it goes through v in the middle,
how
has the weight of my path changed? Well, it hasn't,
because I added a number to all outgoing edges.
So there's an outgoing edge here with weight I've
changed by weight h. And there's an incoming edge
here that I've changed by weight negative
h. So these cancel out, and you've got 0.
So passing through a vertex
doesn't change the weight of my path. The only way I could change
the weight of my path is if v is the start vertex or the end vertex.
So it's possible that s is my vertex or t
is my vertex. Well, for any path leaving v,
I will have increased the weight of that path by h, because I added a
weight h to all outgoing edges. So again, while the path weight has changed,
since all of the paths leaving v have changed by
the same amount, a shortest path will still be a
shortest path. And same goes for t. If t, the end
vertex, is v, I'll have subtracted h from all of
my incoming edges, which means that any path ending at t, any directed path ending
at t, also changes by the same value. And so shortest paths must be preserved.
So shortest paths preserved.
So that's pretty cool transformation.
I can assign for any vertex
such a transformation, which affects all of the
edges surrounding it by this h additive factor,
either added or subtracted.
And I can do this independently for every vertex. If shortest paths were
preserved by me doing this to one vertex, then if I do it to another vertex,
then shortest paths are still
preserved. And let's prove that real quick.
What
I'm going to do is I'm going to want to do this to give me flexibility
for changing all the edge weights in my graph to have this property.
I'm going to set
or define
a potential
function
h that maps
vertices to integers.
So I'm going to set a number, an h for
each vertex. These are independent now.
And I'm going to add that potential to all outgoing edges. And
I'm going to subtract that potential from all incoming edges.
This transformation is going
to preserve shortest paths.
be a little bit more rigorous that that's
the case when we do this multiple times.
So claim
shortest paths are
still preserved.
Well, that's, again, not so difficult
to see. So let's consider a path
from s to t,
passes through a bunch of
vertices. I'm going to label these as
v0 to vk so that I
can kind of number them.
This is v1 here. This
is a directed path.
v1, 2, 3, 4, 5, all the way up to
k. There are k edges in this graph.
I claim to you that any path from v0 to vk, any shortest path from v0
to vk remains the shortest path after I reweight everything in this way.
So let's say this is path
pi. And so it has weight w pi,
which is really just the sum of all of the edge
weights from vi minus 1 to vi for i equals 1 to k.
This is poor notation. This is the weight of the edge
from vi minus 1 to i. And we've got indexes from 1.
That's the first edge to
k, which is the last edge.
So that's the weight of my path.
The weight of my transformed path,
I'm going to do it down here. It's
a little iffy. The weight of my transformed path, I'm going
to say is the weight in this new reweighted graph, g prime.
This weight of that same
path, it's the same path,
is just going to be the sum
of all of the reweighted
edges. So i equals 1 to k
of my original weight of my
edge, so from 0 i minus 1 to vi.
But what did I do?
This edge is outgoing
from vi minus 1.
It's outgoing, so I add
that weight, that potential,
sorry.
But that edge is also incoming into vi. So when I
reweighted the thing, I got a subtraction of h vi.
Now,
what happens here in the sum, this term if I just took the sum
over this term, that's exactly my original pathway. So that's good.
But you'll notice that
this sum has k terms.
And this sum has the subtraction of
k other terms. But most of these terms
are equal. Along the path, all
the incoming and outgoing edges
cancel out. So
we're left with only
adding the potential at the starting vertex and subtracting
the potential at the final vertex. So we've got add h v0
minus h vk.
And why is that good?
Well, that's good because every path from v0 to
vk starts at v0 and ends at vk. That's how it is.
That's how we've defined
paths going from v0 to vk.
But every such path,
we transform the weight of that path by adding a constant associated
with the start and adding this value associated with the end.
So every path going from v0 to
vk changes by the same amount.
And so if this path
p pi was shortest,
it's still shortest in the reweighted graph because I've just
changed all paths between those two vertices by the same amount.
This is kind of like a telescoping argument here
in that kind of proof. So we have the weight
changes. It could change. But it changes all paths
between these two vertices by the same amount,
which means that shortest
paths are still shortest.
Awesome.
OK.
So
the name of the game here is now we have this
really flexible tool. We have this tool where we can
add or subtract weight from various edges. But we have to do so in a kind of
localized, constrained way. We have to do the same thing around each vertex.
But it seems like a powerful transformation
technique that maybe we can get this thing that we
want, which is a g prime, a reweighting of the graph
where all the edge weights are positive or non -negative.
So does there
exist an h such that
the weights are all positive?
What does that mean? w prime uv,
the weight in my
new graph in g prime,
I want these
modified weights,
this modified weight of my
graph, I want each of these to
be non -negative.
So does there
exist such a thing?
Well, if I rearrange this
equation a little bit, this side,
I get something
that looks like this.
h of v
needs to be less than
or equal to h of u plus
the weight of some
edge from u to v.
What does that look like?
That looks like almost exactly the
definition of the triangle inequality.
Shortest path from some vertex here and its shortest path distance from
the same vertex here, this is just a statement of the triangle inequality.
So if we can set these h's to be the shortest path distance
from some vertex, and those shortest path distances are finite,
and not minus infinity,
then this thing will hold by triangle inequality.
And in particular, if we were to reweight the
edges based on those values of h, then we'd
get new edge weights that are non -negative.
Awesome. OK.
But there might not be any vertex from which we can access. Which we can reach
all vertices in the graph. In particular, my graph might not even be connected.
If I want this property, I need all of these. I don't
gain any information if these things are infinite.
It's exhaustively true. Infinity is, I don't even know how to
compare infinity and infinity plus a constant. I don't know.
So I need all of these things to be finite.
So how can I make those things finite?
So here's the next idea.
Add
new vertex
s
with
zero weight edge
to every vertex
v in v. We take our original graph. We add a
new super node or auxiliary vertex s with a zero
weight edge to every vertex in my graph. What does that
look like? This is like, there's my original graph.
And now I have this vertex s. But it has directed
edges into all of the vertices. With zero weight.
That's our picture.
And this new thing,
I'm going to call
maybe my s graph now.
And
the claim is, well, now if I run some shortest
path algorithm, single source shortest path
algorithm this time, from s to compute the shortest path distance to all of the
vertices, the shortest path distance to each of the vertices can't be positive,
right? Because
there's a zero weight edge. So a minimum
weight path is going to be no bigger than zero.
If it's finite, then there's a finite length
shortest path. If it's minus infinity,
then there's a negative
weight cycle in my graph.
So there
are either two situations.
If
delta sv equals minus
infinity, so I guess this is
run
single source
shortest paths from s.
And really, because this graph could contain
negative edge weights and could contain negative
cycles, we can't really do better than running
Bellman -Ford here, right, from s to compute these
paths. If there exists in this new graph, this gs, if there exists
a vertex that has negative infinite weight in the reweighted graph,
sorry,
in the original graph, g, g
hasn't been reweighted yet.
If there's a negative
weight distance from s,
then
there was a negative
weight cycle in
the original graph. Why is that?
Well, if this was set to minus infinity, then
there is some negative weight cycle in the graph,
right? The worry is that that negative weight cycle
was added to my graph by adding this vertex s.
But what do I know about vertex s? It has no
incoming edges, right? So no negative weight cycle
could go through s, right? So any negative weight
cycle was in the original graph, and so I can abort.
Abort.
Yay.
Otherwise?
What do I do? Well, I know
these shortest path distances here
would satisfy the triangle
inequality, right? So if I reweight
with
h of v equal to delta s of v,
right, if we set our potentials in our reweighted graph
to be the shortest path distance from our supernode s,
it satisfies the
triangle inequality,
right?
And because there's no negative cycles, all of these values are finite. And
then this reweighting will lead to a graph with strictly, or not strictly,
strictly no negative weights or
non -negative weights. OK, great.
So that's basically it.
That's the idea behind
Johnson's algorithm.
It's really a reduction problem, a reduction
algorithm. We're reducing from solving
kind of signed
all -pair shortest paths, graphs where
their weights could be positive or negative,
and we're reducing to creating a graph
that has the same shortest paths properties
but only has non -negative edge weights. So we're reducing
from a signed context to a non -negative weight context, right?
So Johnson's algorithm, what
are the steps?
Gs from g,
right,
just as up here, right?
I make a new vertex s.
I put a zero -weight directed edge from s to
every vertex. OK, so that's the first step.
Second step,
compute ds
v for all v in V,
IE or EG. I guess, really, it should be IE because
I don't really have another option here, but by
Bellman -Ford.
This is just a single
run of Bellman -Ford here.
Compute.
And then there are
two possibilities.
If
there exists a delta
sv that's minus infinity,
then abort.
Else,
make
our reweight the graph according
to this reweighting scheme, right?
By reweighting each
edge
in my original
graph to have weight,
our new weight, which
is our old weight,
plus our transformation. Now, our transformation is now going
to set Hv to this delta sv, right? So I'm going to add delta
su and subtract delta sv.
That's our reweighting scheme. I'm just identifying
Hv with this shortest path distance here, OK?
And after I reweighted
that, I can just solve
all pair shortest paths
on G prime with Dijkstra.
And then
compute
G shortest path distances
from
G prime shortest
path distances, right?
Compute these
distances from the other
using this algorithm up here. Can compute distances
in G from distances in G prime in linear time.
Or, sorry, v times linear time.
Linear time for each s,
for each vertex in my graph.
OK. So that's the algorithm.
Basically, correctness is trivial, right? We
already proved the whole part of this lecture, the
interesting part of this lecture, was proving that
if we had a transformation based on a potential
function that changed outgoing edges in a
symmetrically opposite way as incoming edges,
then that preserves
shortest paths.
And then realizing that
the triangle inequality enforces this condition that edge
weights will be positive or non -negative under this reweighting.
So we find shortest path distances from some other arbitrary vertex and set our
potential functions to be those shortest path distance weights. We do the reweighting.
Because that reweighting preserves
shortest paths, which we already argued,
right?
It does positive edge weight. So Dijkstra applies. And then computing this
takes a small amount of time. OK. What is the running time of this algorithm?
So this part, reconstructing this thing, this
takes linear time, right? I'm just adding.
I'm just making a new graph of the same
size except I added v edges and one vertex.
OK. Computing, doing Bellman -Ford on this new modified graph,
that's just, I'm doing that once. That takes v times e time.
Doing
this check,
that just takes, I'm looping over
my vertices. That just takes v time.
Otherwise,
doing this reweighting, I change the weight
of every edge. That takes order e time.
And then solving g prime
solving all pair shortest paths on the modified edge weight graph with Dijkstra
takes v times Dijkstra, right? That's, use a little bit more board space here.
That's v
times v log
v plus e time, right? Which is actually the running
time that we were looking for, right? I wanted
to reduce to not using more than this time. We
used this amount of time. Let's make sure we still
didn't use even more. After that, we compute these
paths as proved before in v times v plus e, which
is smaller than that, right? And so
summing up all of these running times,
this one dominates.
So Johnson's can solve signed
weighted all pair shortest paths,
signed all pair shortest paths,
not in v times Bellman -Ford
like we had before up here,
but faster in nearly linear for sparse graphs just without
this log factor. So we got quite a big improvement, right?
So that's the nice thing about all pair shortest
paths is that really we don't have to incur this
big cost in the context of negative weights.
Essentially, we just run Bellman -Ford once to see if
there is a negative weight cycle in my graph. If it is, I save a lot of work by
stopping early, OK? So that's Johnson's. That's the end of our graphs lectures.
We'll be having a review and problem session about how
to solve problems, graph problems, using this material.
But we've talked about a lot of different things so far.
We've talked about graph reachability, connected components,
detecting cycles, detecting
topological sort orders of a DAG.
We've talked about finding negative weight cycles,
single source shortest path algorithms. And now,
finally, today, all pair shortest path algorithms,
with a new algorithm that's really not an
entirely new algorithm, right? We didn't
have to do any proof by induction here.
Really, the heavy work that's happening is we're
reducing to using either Dijkstra or Bellman -Ford
to do the heavy lifting of finding single shortest paths
efficiently, right? So Johnson's is really just glue to
transform a graph in a clever way. And reducing to
using some of these shortest paths algorithms faster,
OK? So that's our unit on graphs. Our next lecture,
we'll start talking about a general form of not
presenting you with an algorithm, but how to design your own algorithm
in the context of dynamic programming, OK? So see you next lecture.